<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[codebreak.er]]></title>
  <link href="http://codebreak.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://codebreak.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-11-19T22:41:08-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://codebreak.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[codebreaker]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Javaland]]></title>
    <link href="http://codebreak.github.com/blog/2013/11/19/javaland/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-19T22:10:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://codebreak.github.com/blog/2013/11/19/javaland</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Simple Start on Java
OCT 31ST, 2013
Java and Gradle
Get Gradle
Create Project directory “MarsRover”
Build Project Structure:
cd MarsRover/ mkdir -p src/main/java mkdir -p src/test/java
Create first java class:
cd src/main/java vi HelloWorld.java
public class HelloWorld{ public static void main(String[] args){ System.out.println(“Hello World!!”);
}
}
Java conventional rules: Allowed only one public class in the file and that class name should match the filename. static means method is not an instance it is attached to the class void means method is not returning anything main mean its the entry point to the app
Build your project: gradle build
:compileJava UP-TO-DATE (compiles java classes – HelloWorld) :processResources UP-TO-DATE :classes UP-TO-DATE (classes depends on compileJava)
:jar UP-TO-DATE (Builds the jar – creates MarsRover.jar with HelloWorld – .zip) :assemble UP-TO-DATE umbrella tasks :compileTestJava UP-TO-DATE
:processTestResources UP-TO-DATE :testClasses UP-TO-DATE :test UP-TO-DATE :check UP-TO-DATE (umbrella for test tasks … i.e. cucumber) :build UP-TO-DATE (umbrella: assemble and check)
this basically creates a .jar file (MarsRover.jar) which is really just a zip file of all your compiled source files. (everything from src/main/java)
Running program: cd build/libs/ java -cp MarsRover.jar HelloWorld</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intel HAXM]]></title>
    <link href="http://codebreak.github.com/blog/2013/03/29/intel-haxm/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-29T15:09:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://codebreak.github.com/blog/2013/03/29/intel-haxm</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One of the biggest pains that I found when I started learning how to build android apps was waiting for the emulator to Launch and startup. Luckily, after having tweeted:</p>

<blockquote><blockquote><p>&ldquo;This #android #emulator sure takes it&rsquo;s time to load. Wish there was some sort of progress bar to indicate that it&rsquo;s not stuck or hanging.&rdquo;</p></blockquote></blockquote>

<p>android sdk</p>

<p>installing HAXM</p>

<p>To verify that Intel HAXM is running, open a terminal window and execute the following command:</p>

<p><code>kextstat | grep intel</code></p>

<p>If Intel HAXM is operating correctly, the command will show a status message indicating that the kernel extension named <code>com.intel.kext.intelhaxm</code> is loaded.</p>

<p>To stop or start Intel HAXM, use the following commands:</p>

<p>Stop:
<code>sudo kextunload –b com.intel.kext.intelhaxm</code></p>

<p>Start:
<code>sudo kextload –b com.intel.kext.intelhaxm</code></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[RapidFTR-Android Setup]]></title>
    <link href="http://codebreak.github.com/blog/2013/03/23/rapidftr-android-setup/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-23T23:29:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://codebreak.github.com/blog/2013/03/23/rapidftr-android-setup</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>git clone git@github.com:rapidftr/RapidFTR&mdash;-Android.git</p>

<p>Set Up instructions:
<a href="https://github.com/rapidftr/RapidFTR---Android/wiki/Project-setup">https://github.com/rapidftr/RapidFTR&#8212;Android/wiki/Project-setup</a></p>

<p>Project Settings: (command, semicolon)
Under Platform Settings, Select SDKs
Make sure an Android SDK is created, if none were created add one by selecting the &lsquo;+&rsquo;.
Select &lsquo;Android SDK&rsquo; and select your SDK.
In the next window, select your Java SDK, Your Build Target and then select &lsquo;OK&rsquo;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[fatal: The remote end hung up unexpectedly]]></title>
    <link href="http://codebreak.github.com/blog/2012/11/14/fatal-the-remote-end-hung-up-unexpectedly/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-14T08:39:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://codebreak.github.com/blog/2012/11/14/fatal-the-remote-end-hung-up-unexpectedly</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Lately I&rsquo;ve been working on a client site &hellip; which entails having to set some proxies. I think for some reason this has conflicted with my github set up. The other day, when I tried a &lsquo;git pull &mdash;rebase&rsquo; I got the &lsquo;fatal: The remote end hung up unexpectedly&rsquo; error. This is what I did to fix the problem.</p>

<p>I checked to see if I had any of my proxies set in my environment:</p>

<pre><code>env | grep -i http
</code></pre>

<p>When I saw that they were set, I went ahead an unset them:</p>

<pre><code>unset http_proxy
unset https_proxy
unset all_proxy
</code></pre>

<p>After unsetting them, I checked if I can do a &lsquo;git pull &mdash;rebase&rsquo; again. Sadly I still got the error. To get around this, I decided to try pulling using https instead of ssh. To do this, I first added it:</p>

<pre><code>git remote add origin-https https://github.com/&lt;project_name&gt;/&lt;project_name.git&gt;
</code></pre>

<p>Doing so then allows you to pull from the remote set up &lsquo;origin-https&rsquo;. NOTE: Remember to specify the branch as well (In this case &lsquo;master&rsquo;).</p>

<pre><code>git pull origin-https master
</code></pre>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using RVM]]></title>
    <link href="http://codebreak.github.com/blog/2012/10/28/using-rvm/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-28T09:36:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://codebreak.github.com/blog/2012/10/28/using-rvm</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>RVM stands for Ruby Version Manager. RVM becomes very useful for when you want to use multiple versions of Ruby. If RVM wasn&rsquo;t around, having more than one version of Ruby on your system would be very difficult to deal with. RVM will allow you to have multiple installations of Ruby AND make it easy for you to switch back and forth.</p>

<p>To install a specific (1.9.3) Ruby interpreter:</p>

<pre><code>rvm install 1.9.3
</code></pre>

<p>To check ruby version:</p>

<pre><code>ruby -v
</code></pre>

<p>To check your current ruby path:</p>

<pre><code>which ruby
</code></pre>

<p>To check current installed rubies:</p>

<pre><code>rvm list
</code></pre>

<p>To use system ruby:</p>

<pre><code>rvm use system
</code></pre>

<p>Before you can use a gemset, you must create it:</p>

<pre><code>rvm use 1.9.3@biteme --create
</code></pre>

<p>To view your gemset list:</p>

<pre><code>rvm gemset list
</code></pre>

<p>To use a gemset list:</p>

<pre><code>rvm use 1.9.3@biteme
</code></pre>

<p>To delete a gemset:</p>

<pre><code>rvm gemset delete biteme
</code></pre>

<p>To specify a &lsquo;default&rsquo; gemset for a given interpreter:</p>

<pre><code>rvm use 1.9.3@biteme --default
</code></pre>

<p>To have it so that your gemset is automatically loaded when you enter a directory, you&rsquo;ll need to create or add to your .rvmrc file &lsquo;rvm use 1.9.3@biteme&rsquo;</p>

<pre><code>vi .rvmrc
rvm use 1.9.3@biteme    
</code></pre>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[3 years @ ThoughtWorks]]></title>
    <link href="http://codebreak.github.com/blog/2012/07/20/3-years-at-thoughtworks/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-20T09:41:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://codebreak.github.com/blog/2012/07/20/3-years-at-thoughtworks</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Over 3 years ago, after being laid off from a start up company then deciding to volunteer in Peru and backpack through South America for a few months &ndash; I was basking in the glory of <strong>FUNEMPLOYMENT</strong> when I came across an invitation to a &ldquo;<strong>Super Saturday</strong>&rdquo; interview event at <a href="https://www.thoughtworks.com">ThoughtWorks</a> &ndash; Chicago.</p>

<p>I got flown in and put up at the Club Quarters Hotel in the heart of downtown Chicago. Then during the event, 30-40 candidates got divided into groups and spent the entire day meeting numerous ThoughtWorkers as well participate in various activities like a Lego game and a controversial group discussion.</p>

<blockquote><p>I really appreciated how the main purpose was to not only test my technical abilities but to also determine if I&rsquo;m a good culture fit. Never before have I been thoroughly impressed by the way a company hired people.</p></blockquote>

<p>During my 3 year relationship with ThoughtWorks, I have worked on <strong>4 billable projects</strong> as well as numerous side projects in <strong>5 different countries</strong>. I have met countless intellectual co-workers (now friends) from all over the world and I can honestly say that I have learned something from each one of them.</p>

<h2>Assignment in Calgary, Canada (Oct09-March10)</h2>

<ul>
<li><strong><em>Role</em>:</strong> Tester</li>
<li><strong><em>Test Stack</em>:</strong> QTP for test automation</li>
<li><strong><em>Learnings</em>:</strong>

<ul>
<li>On my very first project, I had the opportunity to work with a dominantly ThoughtWorks team and learn so much about an array of different roles from amazing people like Jane Robarts (Delivery Assurance and my original sponsor), Mikey Aquilar (Project Coach and my current sponsor), Vijay Seetaram (Iteration Manager), Juanjuan Zang (BA), and Radu Muresan (kick ass DEV).</li>
<li>Within just a few days, it also became apparent that ThoughtWorks is a flat organization and that though there are leads on a project, there is no need to sit around and wait for anyone to tell you what to do. You can (and should) simply just get up and start getting shit done.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong><em>Project Status</em>:</strong> ThoughtWorks deemed the project &ldquo;successful&rdquo; considering we delivered what we said we would &ndash; the company division has however been shut down.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Assignment in San Francisco, California (May-Sept10)</h2>

<ul>
<li><strong><em>Role</em>:</strong> Mobile Tester</li>
<li><strong><em>Test Stack</em>:</strong> Ruby/RSpec, Cucumber &amp; Frank (iOS)</li>
<li><strong><em>Learnings</em>:</strong>

<ul>
<li>Was lucky enough to be present during the creation of the iOS Test Automation Framework called <a href="http://testingwithfrank.com/">Frank</a> created by fellow ThoughtWorker <a href="http://blog.thepete.net/">Pete Hodgson</a> &amp; Derek Longmuir.</li>
<li>iOS application testing opens up an array of issues that greatly differ from web testing. (More on this later)</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong><em>Project Status</em>:</strong> Product Successfully launched and is currently one of the top 100 iPad apps in the AppleStore.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Assignment in Melbourne, Australia (Oct10-June11)</h2>

<ul>
<li><strong><em>Role</em>:</strong> Tester and Coach</li>
<li><strong><em>Test Stack</em>:</strong> Ruby/RSpec, Cucumber, Capybara &amp; WebDriver</li>
<li><strong><em>Learnings</em>:</strong>

<ul>
<li>Mobile (non-native app) automated tests are easy to write when using the Web Browser. But, manual testing will always need to be done on an actual device which can eventually become cumbersome.</li>
<li>Meticulous implementation/testing is important &ndash; however, one should consider being a bit more lenient when dealing with mobile apps where an app&rsquo;s average life expectancy is 14 about months.</li>
<li>Learned that consulting is hard and that before you can be taken seriously &hellip; you need to earn the client&rsquo;s trust first.</li>
<li>There are defined roles on a project but a role is not meant to be done by one person. The team should work together to fill in each role.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong><em>Project Status</em>:</strong> The team successfully delivered the product as specified by the client however, the client had no marketing strategy to move forward and in the end the product was scrapped.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Assignment in Bangalore, India &amp; Xian, China (Aug-Nov11)</h2>

<ul>
<li><strong><em>Role</em>:</strong> Coach and Trainer</li>
<li><strong><em>Test Stack</em>:</strong> Python, Django</li>
<li><strong><em>Learnings</em>:</strong>

<ul>
<li>Distributed projects can work so long as you&rsquo;re in the same (or close enough) time zone so that can flow back and forth easily.</li>
<li>Make a few changes in your teaching style when english is not the first language of those you are teaching.</li>
<li>Speaking in public is not so hard when you take your time, practice &hellip; and picture the audience is naked &hellip; I mean, interested.</li>
<li>You need to toughen up to survive in China &hellip; speaking the language can&rsquo;t hurt either.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong><em>Project Status</em>:</strong> 15 new ThoughtWorkers were released to the world and the project we worked on is currently still getting worked on by a team in Pune, India.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Assignment in San Francisco &amp; Los Angeles, California (Dec11-June12)</h2>

<ul>
<li><strong><em>Role</em>:</strong> Tester &amp; Business Analyst</li>
<li><strong><em>Test Stack</em>:</strong> Ruby, Cucumber, Capybara, WebDriver &amp; Frank (iOS Testing Tool)</li>
<li><strong><em>Learnings</em>:</strong>

<ul>
<li>Releasing a product SOONER provides feedback and is much more effective than striving for perfection before launching.</li>
<li>Realized the importance of an inception to define some sort of an MVP (Minimal Viable Product).</li>
<li>There needs to be an agreed upon plan to do proper hand over to increase the likelihood that it will be a sustainable project.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong><em>Project Status</em>:</strong> ThoughtWorks has handed over the working application to the client and we believe implementation is currently still in progress.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[WebDriver: Making the switch to ChromeDriver]]></title>
    <link href="http://codebreak.github.com/blog/2012/07/11/firefox-vs-chromedriver/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-11T00:05:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://codebreak.github.com/blog/2012/07/11/firefox-vs-chromedriver</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On my previous project I used Cucumber on top of Capybara to driver out WebDriver. We were initially going to use ChromeDriver instead of the default FireFox &hellip; but I decided at the last minute to stick with Firefox.</p>

<p>Recently, I heard rumors that ChromeDriver is &ldquo;Faster&rdquo; than Firefox. So, like the curious person that I am, I decided to switch out FireFox for ChromeDriver to test out this claim.</p>

<h3>Setting up Cucumber to use ChromeDriver</h3>

<p>To make the switch, all I had to do was replace the driver definition from:</p>

<pre><code>Capybara.current_driver = :selenium 
</code></pre>

<p>to:</p>

<pre><code>Capybara.register_driver :chrome do |app|
    Capybara::Selenium::Driver.new(app, :browser =&gt; :chrome)
  end
Capybara.javascript_driver = :chrome
</code></pre>

<p>Then in all my Cucumber feature files, I added the tag @javascript:</p>

<h3>Re-run Cucumber Feature Files</h3>

<p>When I re-ran my Cucumber Features files using ChromeDriver, I however came across a few errors:</p>

<pre><code>focusElement execution failed;
   Failed to send keys because cannot focus element (Selenium::WebDriver::Error::UnknownError)
</code></pre>

<blockquote><p>Apparently, You can&rsquo;t use send_keys for certain types of inputs. (Workaround &ndash; click the element and then use the advanced interactions API to send keys without an element.)</p></blockquote>

<pre><code>Element is not clickable at point (928, 23.5). Other element would receive the click
</code></pre>

<blockquote><p>ChromeDriver always clicks the middle of the element in attempt to be faithful to what an actual user does.
There are two ways to handle this currently:</p>

<ul>
<li>Change/fix the page so that the user can click on the link in the middle.</li>
<li>Use the advanced user interactions API to click at the appropriate place in the link. e.g., ActionChains(w).move_to_element_with_offset(link, 0, 20).click().perform()</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>

<h3>Speed Test Results: Firefox vs ChromeDriver</h3>

<p>After fixing the issues above and passing all my tests, I was able to compare their speeds and found that ChromeDriver was 15 &ndash; 20% faster than Firefox. With a smaller testsuite, the difference might not make much of a difference but can you imagine the difference on a larger testsuite! In the end &hellip; you have to consider whether Chrome&rsquo;s speedy performance is worth dealing with the issues that seem to be ChromeDriver specific.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Capybara tutorial using irb]]></title>
    <link href="http://codebreak.github.com/blog/2012/06/24/capybara-tutorial-using-irb/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-24T16:03:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://codebreak.github.com/blog/2012/06/24/capybara-tutorial-using-irb</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>At one of my previous projects, a fellow ThoughtWorker named Rob Hunter showed me how to use irb (Interactive Ruby Shell) to play around with a test framework for web applications called <a href="https://github.com/jnicklas/capybara/">Capybara</a>. I&rsquo;ve found it pretty useful so I figured I&rsquo;d share it here.</p>

<p>To get started, make sure you have ruby installed. (Below I am using ruby version 1.9.2 and creating a gemset using RVM)</p>

<pre><code>rvm use 1.9.2@cucumberplay --create
</code></pre>

<p>Install <a href="https://github.com/jnicklas/capybara/">Capybara</a> if you haven&rsquo;t already.</p>

<pre><code>gem install capybara
</code></pre>

<p>Launch irb with the following requirements (ruby, capybara, and capybara/dsl)</p>

<pre><code>irb -r rubygems -r capybara -r capybara/dsl
</code></pre>

<p>Include Cabybara DSL:</p>

<pre><code>include Capybara::DSL
</code></pre>

<p>Set the default driver.</p>

<pre><code>Capybara.default_driver = :selenium
</code></pre>

<p>Now test that capybara commands work by visiting google</p>

<pre><code>visit "http://www.google.com"
</code></pre>

<h2>Here&rsquo;s an example for logging into GMAIL</h2>

<pre><code>visit "http://www.gmail.com"
page.has_content?("A Google approach to email.")

fill_in 'Email', :with =&gt; "johnjames4343@gmail.com"
fill_in 'Passwd', :with =&gt; "johnjames4u"
click_button 'Sign in'
</code></pre>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Women & Presentations CAN mix]]></title>
    <link href="http://codebreak.github.com/blog/2012/06/09/women-presenters/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-09T15:50:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://codebreak.github.com/blog/2012/06/09/women-presenters</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.bayareagirlgeekdinners.com/bay-area-girl-geek-dinner-25-sponsored-by-thoughtworks/"><img class="right" src="https://evbdn.eventbrite.com/s3-s3/eventlogos/6471833/screenshot20120828at8.06.17pm.png.jpg" width="200" height="200"></a></p>

<p>After months of planning with my amazing colleagues &ndash; <a href="https://twitter.com/AConnJob">Annie Conn</a>, <a href="http://www.bonnachoi.com">Bonna Choi</a>, and <a href="http://www.nanchu.me/">Nancy Chu</a> &ndash; we successfully organized the first ever <a href="http://www.bayareagirlgeekdinners.com/bay-area-girl-geek-dinner-25-sponsored-by-thoughtworks/">ThoughtWorks sponsored Girl Geek Dinner.</a></p>

<p>Once the venue, catering, and audio/equipment rentals were confirmed &hellip; the next thing on my list was to find <strong>WOMEN</strong> speakers. Much to my surprise this was the hardest part of the organizing bit! When I thought about who I&rsquo;d want to invite to be one of my speakers, I quickly thought of our Chief Technology Officer &ndash; <a href="http://join.thoughtworks.com/profiles/rebecca-parsons">Rebecca Parsons</a>. After jotting down Rebecca, I remember having to really think hard about my next set of speaker prospects. Eventually, I came up with 4-5 potential ThoughtWorks women speakers but all of them were out of state! I could have flown them in but that was not very cost effective so I dropped that idea.</p>

<p>Instead, I decided to look within the ThoughtWorks San Francisco community. By doing so, I was faced with a lot of the same excuses &hellip; <strong>&ldquo;I can&rsquo;t, I have other plans that day.&rdquo;</strong>, <strong>&ldquo;I would, but I don&rsquo;t know what I&rsquo;d talk about.&rdquo;</strong> and perhaps the most common one of all (which coincidentally was my excuse as  well) &hellip;</p>

<blockquote><p><strong>I&rsquo;ve never done a talk in front of a large audience and I&rsquo;m utterly terrified of speaking in public.</strong></p></blockquote>

<p>OK so you&rsquo;ve never done it before. That&rsquo;s fine &hellip; so let&rsquo;s start at a smaller scale and work our way up. How about we start with speaking out more during the day. Make yourself heard in meetings and team conversations or even talk to a team member you don&rsquo;t usually talk to. Discuss <strong>WHAT</strong> you&rsquo;re working on and as well as <strong>HOW</strong> you&rsquo;re getting things done to those outside of your team. By doing so, I think you&rsquo;ll find that your communication skills will improve and &hellip;</p>

<blockquote><p><strong>other&rsquo;s will learn and get inspired by the knowledge and experiences you&rsquo;ve shared with them.</strong></p></blockquote>

<p>Realizing that you have something worthwhile to say will help you gain the <strong>CONFIDENCE</strong> that you need to speak in front of people. Your experiences and lessons learned can serve as your topics. With your topics at hand and armed with confidence &hellip; all that&rsquo;s really left is polishing up your presentation skills.</p>

<p>Now don&rsquo;t be fooled &hellip; when I signed up to do my <strong>FIRST EVER</strong> tech talk for Girl Geek Dinners I was not completely at ease. In fact I was still pretty nervous. But if there&rsquo;s one thing I&rsquo;ve learned &ndash; like many people &hellip;<strong> I will always be nervous when it comes to speaking in front of people </strong> but I&rsquo;m not going to let that prevent me from getting up there and doing it anyways!</p>

<p>So get out there, challenge your self by doing a presentation or 2. And maybe &hellip; just maybe you&rsquo;ll get to a point where you&rsquo;re a little less nervous than your very first presentation/talk.</p>

<h2>Step #1 Sign up for presentations</h2>

<ul>
<li>Teach or train a fellow team member.</li>
<li>Start <a href="http://www.pecha-kucha.org/">Pecha Kucka Nights</a> with a group of people.</li>
<li>Hold workshops on topics that other people could benefit from.</li>
<li>Hold brown bags (people bring in lunch while someone does a presentation).</li>
<li>Participate in Lightning talks (Very short 5-10 min talks on a particular topic).</li>
</ul>


<h2>Step #2 Preparation is key</h2>

<ul>
<li>Do the necessary research or find supporting artifacts to get your point across.</li>
<li>If you&rsquo;re using slides during your presentation &ndash; make sure they are there only to support your talk &hellip; NOT control it. Keep it simple with as few words as possible. (Photos wont hurt either)</li>
<li>Most Power point tools these days timers &hellip; USE THEM when you&rsquo;re practicing AND during your talk!</li>
<li>Practice, Practice, Practice! Practice in front of a mirror or better yet, do a dry run in front of someone.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Step #3 Rock It!</h2>

<ul>
<li>Engage the audience, ask them questions and make them feel like they&rsquo;re having a conversation with you instead of it being a one way street.</li>
<li>Speak slowly and annunciate. It may sound odd to you at first (and maybe it does) but at least people will be able to follow and listen to what you have to say.</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t read your notes &hellip; I know its terrifying but trust me &hellip; its better if you try to memorize everything!</li>
</ul>


<h2>Tips for when you get nervous &hellip;</h2>

<ul>
<li>If you get nervous (which I usually do right before I get up) I focus and control my breathing.</li>
<li>Find someone you know and just talk as if you&rsquo;re telling them a story. (If you don&rsquo;t know anyone &hellip; try to find someone that looks nice and interested.)</li>
<li>Pump yourself up and remind your inner self that:

<ol>
<li> These people are here to learn from you &hellip; not to judge you.</li>
<li> Your presentation is based on your experience, knowledge and quite frankly your own opinion or take on a specific topic. So technically you&rsquo;re the subject matter expert in the room!</li>
<li> This will be all over soon &hellip; hang in there!</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Tester Role on an Agile Project]]></title>
    <link href="http://codebreak.github.com/blog/2012/06/08/tester-role/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-08T22:54:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://codebreak.github.com/blog/2012/06/08/tester-role</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Below are examples of what I personally strive for when I&rsquo;m on an agile project. Do note that the role that a tester plays on a project varies and can depend on the tester or the unique dynamics of the team.</p>

<ul>
<li>Show interest in participating on project <strong>Inceptions</strong> and always accept when invited!</li>
<li>Provide tester input when the team is holding their story <strong>Estimation</strong> Sessions.</li>
<li>Be present in team IPMs ( <strong>Iteration Planning Meetings</strong> ) to gain familiarity with the upcoming stories.</li>
<li>Pair with the BAs in writing the <strong>Acceptance Criteria</strong> so that missed scenarios can be identified.</li>
<li>Hold <strong>Story Kickoffs</strong> with a BA and the Developer that has picked up the story.</li>
<li><strong>Pair</strong> with Developers in writing their tests.</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t wait till stories are &ldquo;Ready to Test&rdquo;. Pull the latest and greatest on your local or Test Environment and <strong>start testing early</strong>! (No defects should be created at this time, simply notify the Devs about the issues/concerns found.)</li>
<li>Once Dev&rsquo;s believe that their stories are &ldquo;Ready to Test&rdquo;, hold <strong>Desk-checks</strong> with them and a BA to make sure that they&rsquo;ve implemented the stories according to the Acceptance Criteria.</li>
<li><strong>Automate</strong> functional tests. (Pair with Devs as much as possible when doing this!)</li>
<li>Perform <strong>Exploratory</strong> Testing on stories and push back stories when blocking issues associated to the stories are found.</li>
<li>Log <strong>Defects</strong> for issues not blocking stories or those that are new/regression issues.</li>
<li>Encourage the client to verify stories on Pre-Production and to push to Production as often as possible.</li>
<li>Perform <strong>Smoke Tests</strong> on the Production Environment.</li>
<li>Pair with <strong>Dev Ops</strong> to make sure the necessary Environments are created with appropriate data and automated tests.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hello World!!]]></title>
    <link href="http://codebreak.github.com/blog/2012/06/07/hello-world/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-07T00:05:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://codebreak.github.com/blog/2012/06/07/hello-world</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Much love to @scottmuc for helping me setup my octopress blog!! :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
